John L. Spivak Papers
John L. Spivak Papers
- Correspondence-subject files
  - WNBC (New York) (Box 12)
  - WNYC (New York) (Box 12)
  - WOR-TV (New York) (Box 12)
  - WPEN (Philadelphia) (Box 12)
  - WTTW-TV (Chicago) (Box 12)
  - W. Colston Leigh, Inc. (Box 12)
  - Warner Bros. Pictures, See also Vitagraph, Inc. (Box 12)
  - Warriner, Kate (Box 12)
  - Waymack, W.W. (Box 12)
  - Weiner, Herman (Box 12)
  - Weinzieherowa, Celina (Box 12)
  - Wexley, John (Box 12)
  - White, Leonard H. (Box 12)
  - White House: Roosevelt Administration (Box 12)
  - Whittaker, Otto (Box 12)
  - Willey, Malcolm M., See Plankett, Mercer (Spivak alias)
  - Wilson, Walter (Box 12)
  - Winter, Ella (Box 12)
  - Wichita Beacon, See also Foulston, Siefkin, Foulston & Morris (attorneys); Sepmeier, Kurt A.; University of Wichita (Box 12)
  - Wolfson, P. J. (Box 12)
  - Wood, John S. (Congress.), See Plankett, Mercer (Spivak alias)
  - Xerox (Box 12)
  - Year Magazine, A (Box 12)
  - Z, 1 general folder (Box 12)
  - Zapler, Max C. (Box 12)
  - Zoty Publishing Corporation (Box 12)
  - Unidentified, 1 folder (Box 12)
  - Third-party correspondence (Box 12)
- Writings (as John L. Spivak)
  - Books
    - America Faces the Barricades (Covici Friede Publishers), drafts; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Devil's Brigade (Brewer and Warren), dust jacket; 1 folder (Box 13)
    - Europe Under the Terror (Simon and Schuster), drafts; folders 1-4 (Box 13)
    - Europe Under the Terror (Simon and Schuster), drafts; folders 5-10 (Box 14)
    - Europe Under the Terror, dust jacket; 1 folder (Box 14)
    - Honorable Spy (Modern Age Books, Inc.), galley proofs; 1 folder (Box 15)
    - A Man in His Time (Horizon Press), notes; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - A Man in His Time, drafts; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - A Man in His Time, manuscript; folder 1 of 8 (Box 15)
    - A Man in His Time, manuscript; folders 2-8 (Box 16)
    - A Man in His Time, unused material; folders 1-6 (Box 17)
    - A Man in His Time, unused material; folders 7-11 (Box 18)
    - A Man in His Time, galley proofs; folders 1-4; See also Oversized materials (Boxes 40-41) (Box 19)
    - A Man in His Time, galley proofs; folders 5-8 (Box 20)
    - A Man in His Time, galley proofs; folders 9-12 (Box 21)
    - Plotting American's Pogroms (New Masses), drafts; 1 folder (Box 22)
    - Plotting American's Pogroms, published book, with notes; 1 folder (Box 22)
    - Secret Armies (Starling Press), documents; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Secret Armies, drafts; 1 folder (Box 22)
    - Secret Armies, notes; 1 folder (Box 22)
    - Shrine of the Silver Dollar (Modern Age Books, Inc.), documents; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Shrine of the Silver Dollar, drafts; 1 folder (Box 23)
    - Shrine of the Silver Dollar, galley proofs; 1 folder (Box 23)
    - Unpublished manuscript: Having Fun, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Unpublished manuscript: Indictment, folders 1-3 (Box 23)
    - Unpublished manuscript: Indictment, folders 4-10 (Box 24)
    - Unpublished manuscript: Indictment, folders 11-15 (Box 25)
    - Unpublished manuscript: Indictment, folders 16-19 (Box 26)
  - Journals
    - The Crisis, 1932 (Box 26)
      Oct.: "The Convict Camp at Buzzard's Roost," p.318.
    - Equity, 1967 (Box 26)
      May-June: "1919: The Year Actors Laid Claim to Their Rights," p.7.
    - Friday, 1941 (Box 26)
      May 9: "They Spy on America," p.5.
    - Ghost Stories, 1929 (Box 26)
      July: "A Ghost Who Dictates Novels," p.38.
    - New Masses, 1939 (Box 26)
      Nov. 21: "The Coughlin Racket," (clipping)
      Nov. 28: "Coughlin's Frenzied Finance," (clipping)
      Dec. 5: "Coughlin's Lawyer Speaks," (clipping)
      Dec 12: "Coughlin and Ford," (clipping)
    - 1940 (Box 26)
      Jan. 2: "The Legal Case Against Coughlin," (partial clipping)
    - Readers Digest, 1934 (Box 27)
      Sept.: "The Rise and Fall of a Tabloid," p.96.
    - 1936 (Box 27)
      Mar.: "Hitler's Racketeers," p.52.
    - True Strange Stories, 1929 (Box 27)
      May: "My Day of Madness," p.45.
  - Newspapers
    - Daily Herald (New York), Feb. 3, 1936 (Box 27)
      "Europe Under the Terror" (first of a series)
    - Daily Worker (New York) (Box 27)
      Article: "The Coughlin Racket," Nov. 18, 1939
      Article: "The Whalen Forgeries Are Exposed!" Aug. 1, 1930
      Articles: including series on the Dies Committee, Mar.-Apr. 1937, Sept. 1938
      Guest column May 1944-Feb. 1945 (2 folders)
    - Evening Tribune (Des Moines, IA), 1922 (Box 27)
      Articles (photostats): Spivak's undercover investigation regarding mental institutions, May 1922-July 1922
    - Express, The (Easton, PA)
      - General, undated (Box 27)
      - Articles (includes articles on Governor Shapp), Jul 1971 (Box 27)
      - "Action! Express" (column), Aug. 1968-Feb. 1969 (Box 27)
        See also Correspondence-subject files: Magazine Sales Promotion Business for clippings on the federal investigation into the magazine sales industry
      - "Action! Express" (column), Jan. 1969-Oct. 1970 (Box 28)
      - "Action! Express" (column), Nov. 1970-May 1972 (Box 29)
      - "Action! Express" (column), Jun 1972-Mar. 1973 (Box 30)
    - London Daily Herald, undated; "Fascist Europe" (Box 30)
    - Sunday Worker (New York), Mar.-Apr. 1937; articles (Box 30)
    - Transcripts (Seattle, WA), Oct. 1938; articles on the Dies Committee (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous, Sept. 1935; Dec. 1939-Feb. 1940; includes articles about Father Coughlin (Box 30)
  - Miscellany, article drafts, notes, pamphlets
    - "America First", undated (Box 30)
    - "Buying judgeships", 1931 (Box 30)
    - "Childhood", undated (Box 30)
    - "Early Newspaper Days", undated (Box 30)
    - "The Great Atlantic City Beauty Pageant Exposé", undated (Box 30)
    - "Notes on J.L.S.' report of his activities on the West Coast", Feb. 17, 1937 (Box 30)
    - "Pattern for American Fascism", undated; typed manuscript (Box 30)
    - "Pattern for American Fascism", Sept. 1947; pamphlet (Box 30)
    - "The 'Save the Country' Racket", Nov. 1948; pamphlet (Box 31)
    - "West Virginia", undated (Box 31)
    - "Whalen", undated (Box 31)
    - Untitled ("Elizabeth Bentley..."), undated (Box 31)
    - Untitled [European travel journal], undated (Box 31)
    - Untitled ["...hour blizzards in 50 below temperatures"], undated (Box 31)
    - Untitled [Notes], Germany, Italy, Nazi infiltration, undated; 4 folders (Box 31)
- Writings (as William Blaise)
  - Journals
    - Fury: Exciting Adventures for Men, 1957 (Box 31)
      Feb.: "Terror Stalks the Streets," p.26. Photocopy.
      June: "The Hottest Thing in Pawtucket," p.9.
      Aug.: "Place Your Bets Gentlemen," p.26.
      Oct.: "Sex Orgies in Philadelphia High Society," p.9 (2 copies).
      Dec.: "Sin-Sex-Vice on New Haven's Barbary Coast," p.26.
    - Man to Man, 1961 (Box 31)
      June: "There's No Hiding Place Out There," p. 18.
      July: "Warning: Secret Ears Can Nail You Even if You Do Watch Out!" p.36.
    - Monsieur: Entertainment for Men of the World, 1960 (Box 31)
      May: "The Dirty Book Racket," p.7.
      July: "Convention Cut-ups," p.5.
      Sept. "McGinnis's Wonderful Bar," p.24.
- Writings (as Howard Booth)
  - Journals
    - Everybody's Weekly (London), 1958 (Box 32)
      Feb. 1: "Abe Lincoln's Ghost," p.8.
      Feb. 8: "How the Keely Machine Rocked a Nation," p. 13.
      Mar. 1: "The Ship That Set the World Guessing," p.8.
      Mar. 15: "The Clothes That Came to Life," p.10.
      June 21: "Trickster - or Saint?" p.8.
      Aug. 2: "The Dead Who Could Not Die," p. 19.
      Sept. 13: "There's No Future in it," p.20.
    - Executive Review (Frigid Fluid Company), 1956 (Box 32)
      "The Marked Cards Industry," p.11 (reprinted from Esquire)
    - Fury: Exciting Adventures for Men, 1956 (Box 32)
      Oct.: "Some of Your Best Friends May Be Card Cheats," p.20. Monroe Fry listed in table of contents, Howard Booth on p.20.
    - Male, 1959 (Box 32)
      June: "The Ragpicker Who Lifted Europe's Wallet," p.26.
    - Man to Man, 1961 (Box 32)
      May: "Hideout for a Deserter," p.12.
    - Men, 1959 (Box 32)
      May: "Spy Ring of French Penal Girls," p.10. Also contains article by Douglas Horrabin, p.34.
    - Strange Stories, 1929 (Box 32)
      Nov.: "He Built a Jail for Himself," p.22.
    - True Action, 1961 (Box 32)
      Oct.: "The French Hostesses Who Gave a Wehrmacht Regiment the Kiss of Death," p.20.
    - True Strange Stories, 1929 (Box 32)
      Aug.: "The Strange Romance of Eleanora Duse and d'Annunzio," p.10.
    - True Weird Stories, 1956 (Box 32)
      Feb.: "Harry Truman and Lincoln's Ghost," p.12.
    - Typed manuscripts, undated (Box 32)
      Monroe Fry/Howard Booth, "The Hoodoo Car That Started World War I," (photocopy)
      Monroe Fry/Howard Booth, "She Saved His Life to Kill Him," (photocopy)
- Writings (as Paul Dinsmore)
  - Journals
    - Typed manuscript, undated; Paul Dinsmore/Monroe Fry, "The Coward Who was a Fighting Fool" (photocopy) (Box 32)
- Writings (as Monroe Fry)
  - Books
    - Sex, Vice and Business (Ballantine Books), drafts; 1 folder (Box 32)
    - Sex, Vice and Business, cover dummy; 1 folder (Box 32)
  - Journals
    - Better Homes and Gardens, 1958 (Box 32)
      Apr.: "...A Town Where the Teacher is the Apple of All Eyes!" p.151.
    - Cavalier, 1962 (Box 32)
      May: "Our Tidal Wave of Bootleg Booze," p.51.
      June: "The Tall Americans," p.65.
    - Esquire, 1953; folders 1-3 (Box 32)
      June: "The Three Last Wide-Open Towns," p.49.
      Sept.: "1953 File: World Slave Trade," p.41.
      Oct.: "The Marriage Brokers," p.66.
      Nov.: "The International White Slave Traffic," p.49.
    - 1954 (Box 32)
      Mar.: "Court for Immoral Women," p.58.
      Aug.: "Houston vs. the Jitters," p.44.
      Sept.: "Oil for Evangeline's Children," p.53.
    - 1955 (Box 32)
      Feb.: "Unsolved Mysteries of Psychic Phenomena," p.38.
      Mar.: "The Hoboken Blues," p.41.
      Nov.: "Please! No Scandal in Adultery," p.82.
      Dec.: "Cross Section U.S.A.: Steeltown," p.126.
    - 1956 (Box 32)
      Jan.: "Lullaby of Broadway," p.48.
    - Esquire, 1956; folders 4-5 (Box 33)
      Feb.: "Cross section U.S.A.: Mill Town," p.90.
      Mar.: "Baltimore's Mermaids," p.82.
      Apr.: "Cross section U.S.A.: Insurance Town," p.62.
      May: "Cross section U.S.A.: Railroad Town," p.91.
      June: "Cross section U.S.A.: Tire Town," p.66.
      July: "Cross section U.S.A.: Camera Town," p.69.
      Sept.: "Cross section U.S.A.: Cigarette Town," p.82.
      Nov.: "Cross section U.S.A.: Coal Town," p.86.
      Dec.: "Who tests the testers?" p.179.
    - 1957 (Box 33)
      Jan. "Cross section U.S.A.: Burlesque Town," p.87.
      Feb.: "Cross section U.S.A.: Electric Town," p.87.
      Mar.: "Cross section U.S.A.: Chemical Town," p.73.
      Apr.: "Cross section U.S.A.: Jewelry Town," p.94.
      May: "Cross section U.S.A.: Sin Town," p.84.
      June: "Cross section U.S.A.: Honeymoon Town," p.114.
      Oct.: "Portrait of the Minister as a Salesman," p.90.
    - For Men Only, 1959 (Box 33)
      Feb.: "The desert rat and his $20,000,000 Christmas bonus," p18.
    - Fury: Exciting Adventures for Men, 1956 (Box 33)
      Oct.: "Some of Your Best Friends May be Card Cheats," p.20
      Monroe Fry listed in table of contents, Howard Booth on p.20
      Dec.: "B-girls, Booze and Bedlam," p.12 (3 copies)
      Jan.: "Battle of the Sexes," p.22.
      Feb.: "Beware of Broadway B-girls," p.37
      Issue also includes article by William Blaise, p.26.
    - Liberty, 1955 (Box 33)
      Apr.: "The Amazing Case of a Heroine That Never Was," p.34.
    - Outdoor Adventures, 1956 (Box 33)
      July: "Off-trail," p.8.
      Apr.: "Port of Waterfront Women," p.34.
    - Real: The Exciting Magazine for Men, 1958 (Box 33)
      Feb.: "How to Cheat at Cards," p.26.
    - See: The New Magazine for Men, 1958 (Box 33)
      Mar.: "How to Ask for and Get a Raise," p.26.
    - Typed manuscripts, undated (Box 33)
      Monroe Fry/Howard Booth, "The Hoodoo Car That Started World War I"
      Monroe Fry/Howard Booth, "She Saved His Life to Kill Him"
      Monroe Fry/Paul Dinsmore, "The Coward Who was a Fighting Fool"
      Monroe Fry/Shelby Ogden, "The Waiter Who Bossed a Nation"
- Writings (as Paul Harris)
  - Journals
    - "The Bell Witch" (publication source unknown), undated (Box 33)
- Writings (as Douglas Horrabin)
  - Journals
    - Men, 1959 (Box 33)
      May: "The Plot to Bury China in Money," p.34. (photocopy)
- Writings (as Al Lippencott)
  - Journals
    - Caper, 1962 (Box 34)
      Jan.: "The Lover and the Law," p.5.
      Feb.: "Harvard's School of Murder," p.34.
- Writings (as Leslie Lippencott)
  - Journals
    - True Strange, 1956 (Box 34)
      Oct.: "When the Vampire Wept," p.32.
    - True Weird, 1956 (Box 34)
      May: "Hollywood's Greatest Murder Mystery," p.27.
- Writings (as Sherman L. North)
  - Journals
    - Man to Man, 1961 (Box 34)
      Apr. "Strange Adventures of Marriage Brokers," p.18.
- Writings (as Shelby Ogden)
  - Journals
    - Typed manuscript, undated (Box 34)
      Monroe Fry/Shelby Ogden, "The Waiter Who Bossed a Nation," (photocopy)
- Memorabilia
  - Articles about Spivak
    - Clippings, 1930-1971; 6 folders; See also Oversized Materials (Box 41) (Box 34)
  - Book publicity
    - Europe Under the Terror, 1936 (Box 34)
    - Honorable Spy, undated (Box 34)
    - A Man in His Time, 1967 (Box 34)
    - Secret Armies, undated (Box 35)
    - Sex, Vice and Business (as Monroe Fry), 1959 (Box 35)
    - Shrine of the Silver Dollar, 1940 (Box 35)
  - Book reviews
    - America Faces the Barricades, 1935 (Box 35)
    - Europe Under the Terror, 1936 (Box 35)
    - Georgia Nigger, 1932-1933 (Box 35)
    - Honorable Spy, 1939-1940 (Box 35)
    - A Man in His Time, 1967 (Box 35)
    - Secret Armies, 1938-1939; 3 folders (Box 35)
    - Sex, Vice and Business (as Monroe Fry), 1959 (Box 36)
  - Financial and legal materials
    - Certificates
      - Copy of Spivak's birth certificate; marriage certificate, 1923; 1926 (Box 36)
    - Lectures
      - W. Colston Leigh, Inc., 1935-1937; 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Litigation
      - "In the Matter of Requisition for the Extradition of John L. Spivak", Apr. 1940 (Box 36)
      - "Mutschinski v. Covici-Friede, Inc. and John L. Spivak", June 30, 1936 (Box 36)
    - Publishers
      - American Mercury, Inc., 1934-1935 (Box 36)
      - Better Homes & Gardens, 1957-1958 (Box 36)
      - Brandt & Brandt (agent), 1958-1964 (Box 36)
      - Daily Herald, 1936 (Box 36)
      - Daily Worker, 1932 (Box 36)
      - Esquire Inc., 1938-1957 (Box 36)
      - Horizon Press, Inc., 1965; 1967 (Box 36)
      - Male Publishing Corp., 1958; 1959 (Box 36)
      - Modern Age Books, Inc., 1938-1939 (Box 36)
      - Simon & Schuster, Inc., 1936 (Box 36)
      - Weider Periodicals, Inc., 1959 (Box 36)
      - Zenith Publishing Corp., 1958; 1959 (Box 36)
    - Travel
      - Europe trip, 1938 (Box 36)
      - Passports, 1931; 1935 (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous, 1933-1967 (Box 36)
  - Journal article publicity
    - New Masses (re: Father Charles E. Coughlin articles), Nov. 1939 (Box 36)
  - Lecture publicity
    - Announcements and flyers (W. Colston Leigh, Inc.), 1936-1939; 1967 (Box 36)
  - Newspaper article publicity
    - Daily Worker: Georgia Nigger installments, undated (Box 36)
  - Photographs
    - Secret Armies, (photographs taken for the book), undated (Box 37)
    - Spivak family, undated; parents, wife, daughter, grandson (Box 37)
    - Spivak portraits, 1930-1966 (Box 37)
    - Spivak portrait for A Man in His Time book jacket (includes sketch), 1966 (Box 37)
    - Spivak with others, 1922; undated; includes testifying before the Fisk Congressional Committee regarding the New York City Police Commissioner Whalen forgeries, with Sid Hatfield, movie actor Lionel Stander, visiting a coal mine in Colorado, and various others (Box 37)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; includes postcards of artwork, coal mines in Colorado, and architecture in Germany; See also Oversized materials (Box 40) (Box 37)
    - Photographs (test strips and negatives) taken in the U.S., Europe, and Mexico, undated (Box 38A, 38B)
  - Printed material, 1932-1970; 5 folders
    - Articles from Hebrew newspapers, n.d.; The American Spectator, vol. 1, no. 1, Nov. 1932; Haldeman-Julius Monthly, June 1926; In Fact bound volumes (1945-1947); Cunard White Star Ship menus (1938); Reynolds Metal Company packet; Author's Guild petition; announcements (Box 39)
  - Oversized materials
    - Portrait/book jacket plate for A Man in His Time; photographs from Georgia Nigger; photographs of Spivak's parents, wife, and daughter taken by Spivak (c1931); "History's Mysteries: Chain Gangs" (videocassette), n.d. (Box 40)
    - Issues of Friday (1940-1941); photostats of newspapers with articles about Spivak (1924); sample book jackets for A Man in His Time, Issues of Friday removed for cataloging 7/28/06 PB (Box 41)